expatistan.com 2019-03-03

# Expatistan :: International Cost of Living comparisons

In Expatistan (We or us) we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy

This policy (together with our [disclaimer](https://www.expatistan.com/disclaimer) and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us through our website, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. By visiting this website you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

We may amend this privacy policy at any time. Any changes we may make will be posted on this page, so please check back frequently. Your continued use of our website(s) after posting will constitute your acceptance of, and agreement to, any changes.

For the purpose of the Data Protection regulations, Gerardo Robledillo Gomez, with registered office at Šumavská 1081/10, 120 00, Praha 2 – Vinohrady, Organization Id No.: 747 10 761 is the provider of the service Expatistan, and hereby informs you about the manner and scope of processing the personal data of users of Expatistan, including the scope of Expatistan's users' rights in relation to such processing. 

## Information we may collect about you

We may collect and process the following information about you:

### Information you provide to us

You may provide us with information by filling in forms on our website or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail, live-chat or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register for an account, get a salary calculation, sign up to receive updates from us and when you report a problem with our site. The personal information you provide may include your name, address, e-mail address, credit card information and other information about yourself to enable us to provide you with our price information, price comparison, salary calculation services or other related services. 

### Information we collect about you

When you visit our website(s) we may automatically collect information about your computer, including your IP address, information about your visit, your browsing history, and how you use our website.

### Information we receive from other sources

We work with third parties (including, for example, business partners, service providers, advertising networks, and analytics providers) and may receive information about you from them. This may be combined with other information you provide to us, as described above.

## How we use your personal information

We use personal information about you in connection with the following purposes:

  * Fulfiling your requests: 
    * to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us, including providing you with price information, cost of living comparisons and salary calculations; and 
    * to complete any transaction you are undertaking with us; and
    * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * Marketing: 
    * to provide you with information about goods or services that may interest you;
    * to send you cost-of-living updates and other newsletter content, when you have chosen to receive them.
  * Service Improvements and account management: 
    * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 
    * to administer our site and for internal business administration and operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes; and 
    * to notify you about changes to our service and to send you service emails relating to your account;
    * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure; and
    * to manage and operate your account with us.

## Sharing your personal information

We may share your personal information with third parties in the following circumstances:

  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you. 
  * Advertisers and advertising networks and other third parties that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. 
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site. Your personal information is generally shared in a form that does not directly identify you. 
  * We may also share your personal information with third parties: 
    * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets, along with its professional advisers. If Expatistan or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, personal information held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets. 
    * If required in order to obtain professional advice.
    * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Expatistan, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection. 

We may also share with third parties aggregate information or information that does not personally identify you.

As part of running our service, we use the following processors to process your personal data for the following purposes:

  * Advertising 
    * Google AdSense  
Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of our site and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered. Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout.  
Personal data collected may include Cookies and Usage Data. [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout). 
  * Analytics 
    * Google Analytics  
Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the data collected to track and examine the use of this Service, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
Personal data collected may include Cookies and Usage Data. [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). 
  * Handling payments  
Payment processing services allow us to process payments by credit card or other means. To ensure greater security, we do not collect any payment information directly, other than the result of the transaction as sent to us by the payment providers. Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to you, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.  
We use the following payment provider services: 
    * Braintree, a payment service provided by Braintree, a division of PayPal, Inc. 
    * PayPal, a payment service provided by PayPal Inc. https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full
  * Hosting and Web Infraestructure  
Hosting and Web infraestructure allow us to host data and files and to serve them to you. They also provide long-term safe storage for our data and files for the purpose of backups, as well as providing services to monitor and fix problems in our infraestructure. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.  
We use the following hosting and web infraestructure services: 
    * Linode, a hosting service provided by Linode, LLC. [Privacy Policy](https://www.linode.com/privacy)
    * Amazon Web Services (AWS), a storage and web infraestructure service provided by Amazon.com Inc. [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/). 
    * Honeybadger, a monitoring and alerting service provided by Honeybadger Industries LLC that allow us to handle errors and outages in the Service. [Privacy Policy](https://www.honeybadger.io/privacy/). 
  * Messaging and emailing  
We use messaging and emailing services to deliver e-mail messages to you. In addition to your e-mail address, these services may collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by you, as well as when you interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.  
We use the following messaging and emailing services: 
    * Mandrill, a message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC. [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy)
  * SPAM protection  
SPAM protection services analyze the traffic of our site, potentially containing Users' Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM. 
    * Google reCAPTCHA, a SPAM protection service provided by Google Inc. [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)
  * General Administration  
In order to run the Service in day-to-day operations, we use a suite of tools for document creation, email services, calendar management, etc. 
    * G Suite, a package of cloud-based services for email, chat, video conferences, and real-time document collaborations by Google Inc. [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

By using AdSense on our site personal information may be shared with the following ad technology providers:

## Where we store your personal information

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored in, a country outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. The laws in some countries may not provide as much legal protection for your information as in the EEA. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## Cookies

We use cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website and perform traffic analysis. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse this website. By using our website, you agree to our use of cookies. 

The Website uses cookies to improve user comfort, as allowing them to remember you and your individual settings and preferences. 

A cookie is a simple text file (usually of a few kB) stored on your computer, notebook, or mobile device by the Website able to find and read the cookie. Virtually all web pages use cookies and these files are not harmful to your user system. 

Every cookie is unique to your web browser. The cookie contains certain information such as unique identifier, site name, certain digits and numbers. 

There are two types of cookies - temporary cookies and permanent cookies. Temporary cookies are stored on your device (such as a computer, phone ...) until you leave the Website where they are removed. Such cookies are used by the website to remember information when switching between pages so that there is no need to re-enter or fill in the information again. Permanent cookies remain stored in your device even after you leave the website to remember you as a returning visitor - without identifying a particular person. 

Cookies can be disabled by changing settings in your browser. If you choose to disable cookies, you will not be able to use this website. 

If your Internet browser has cookies enabled, you confirm your consent to the use of cookies on the website. 

For analytical and ad-serving purposes, we use the service provider cookies of

  * Google LLC, located at 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States of America, <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/>

## Opting Out of Collection of Information by Third Parties

Expatistan third-party ad servers, ad network providers, and third-party advertisers (the Ad Providers) may provide you with advertisements that you may see on our website(s) or on other affiliated websites. To improve the relevancy and help measure the effectiveness of such advertisements, the Ad Providers may use cookies, web beacons, clear .gifs or similar technologies. These are used to record users' activity, such as the pages visited, and to learn what types of information are of most interest to the users. Use of these technologies by Ad Providers is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by our privacy policy. For more information regarding the choices you have about these technologies (such as opting-out), click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

## Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information. You can exercise the right at any time by contacting us at gerardo@expatistan.com.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal information to these websites.

## Access to information

You have the right to access personal information held about you by Expatistan. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation. Any access request may be subject to a fee of 10 EUR to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

Updated: 17 May 2018
